<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>duclos.dev</title>
    <link>https://duclos.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on duclos.dev</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 02:01:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://duclos.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Master-Thesis</title>
      <link>https://duclos.dev/posts/ma/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 02:01:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duclos.dev/posts/ma/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://duclos.dev/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duclos.dev/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a Computer and Electrical Engineer from the Technical University of Munich. I was born in the United States, more specifically in Minneapolis. However, I&amp;rsquo;ve lived most of my formative years in Brazil, where my family takes up residence. Eventually, my studies brought me to Germany, but today, I am living in New York and am looking for full-time positions in the region within my background and interests.
Experience   Interests Experience   Operating Systems Linux, FreeRTOS, RTOS   Embedded Systems ARM Cortex MCUs: TM4C123, XMC4500, STM32    FPGAs Microsemi SmartFusion2 Maker Kit, Xilinx Vivado, TCL   Cloud Computing  Terraform, GCP, AWS, Packer    Computer Networking  Unix Sockets, IP/TCP/UDP, DPDK, ZeroMQ    Machine Learning  TensorFlow, TensorFlowLite, TPUs     I&amp;rsquo;ve always been a curious individual, and I believe that trait is not only one of my defining qualities but also one that pushed me to experience as much as I could as an engineer and as a person.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>https://duclos.dev/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duclos.dev/home/</guid>
      <description>Daniel Duclos-Cavalcanti I&amp;rsquo;m a Computer Engineer living in New York with a bachelors and masters from the Technical University of Munich. Currently, collaborating on independent research with Dr.Sivaraman and PhD. Haseeb Ashfaq from Systems@NYU on distributed low-latency networking on the cloud.
The project revolves around Jasper: A Scalable Design and Implementation of a Financial Exchange in the Cloud. Beyond co-authoring and aiding in the development of Jasper, my master thesis constructed a performant heuristic to select VMs based on present cloud conditions to improve Jasper&amp;rsquo;s overall performance, both before and during runtime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://duclos.dev/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duclos.dev/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects FreeRTOS Space-Invaders  A loosely based version of the classic arcade video game developed by Tomohiro Nishikado and released in 1978. The work was written in C and done so as a multi-threaded FreeRTOS application based upon an available emulator.
  C FreeRTOS Multi-threaded  Value Iteration with OpenMPI  An asynchronous value iteration model implemented as a dynamic programming problem. Done so using Open-MPI to distribute the workload across different machines at a cluster made available by the university.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://duclos.dev/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://duclos.dev/resume/</guid>
      <description> #resume embed { width: 100%; height: 1000px; }   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
